[
    {
        "question": "The initial program that is run when the computer is powered up is called __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "boot program",
            "bootloader",
            "initializer"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "bootstrap program",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the software trigger an interrupt?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Sending signals to CPU through bus",
            "Executing a special program called system program",
            "Executing a special program called interrupt trigger program"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Executing a special operation called system call",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a trap/exception?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "hardware generated interrupt caused by an error",
            "user generated interrupt caused by an error",
            "none of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "software generated interrupt caused by an error",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an ISR?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Information Service Request",
            "Interrupt Service Request",
            "Information Service Routine"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Interrupt Service Routine",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an interrupt vector?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "It is a unique device number that is indexed by an address",
            "It is a unique identity given to an interrupt",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "It is an address that is indexed to an interrupt handler",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "DMA is used for __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Low speed devices",
            "Utilizing CPU cycles",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "High speed devices(disks and communications network)",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In a memory mapped input/output __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "the CPU uses polling to watch the control bit constantly, looping to see if a device is ready",
            "the CPU receives an interrupt when the device is ready for the next byte",
            "the CPU runs a user written code and does accordingly"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "the CPU writes one data byte to the data register and sets a bit in control register to show that a byte is available",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In a programmed input/output(PIO) __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "the CPU writes one data byte to the data register and sets a bit in control register to show that a byte is available",
            "the CPU receives an interrupt when the device is ready for the next byte",
            "the CPU runs a user written code and does accordingly"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "the CPU uses polling to watch the control bit constantly, looping to see if a device is ready",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In an interrupt driven input/output __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "the CPU uses polling to watch the control bit constantly, looping to see if a device is ready",
            "the CPU writes one data byte to the data register and sets a bit in control register to show that a byte is available",
            "the CPU runs a user written code and does accordingly"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "the CPU receives an interrupt when the device is ready for the next byte",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the layered approach of Operating Systems __________",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Bottom Layer(0) is the User interface",
            "Bottom Layer(N) is the hardware",
            "Highest Layer(N) is the hardware"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Highest Layer(N) is the User interface",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the Hardware trigger an interrupt?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Executing a special program called interrupt program",
            "Executing a special program called system program",
            "Executing a special operation called system call"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Sending signals to CPU through a system bus",
        "explanation": "None."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operation is performed by an interrupt handler?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Saving the current state of the system",
            "Loading the interrupt handling code and executing it",
            "Once done handling, bringing back the system to the original state it was before the interrupt occurred"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "All of the mentioned",
        "explanation": "None."
    }
]